# RAMDHAN AKBAR BAKHAR

Telepon : 0812-8400-0413

Email : akbarbakhar@gmail.com

LinkedIn : www.linkedin.com/in/RamdhanAB



#### PROFILE

I'm a professional with 5 years of experience at a multinational manufacturing company, I'm familiar to the flow of SOA and SAP systems MB51, MB52 and MIGO, and I'm used to analyzing MES systems, ERP systems.

I have a strong analytical ability and the ability to cooperate in teams and individuals. Addition, I have high discipline I provided by getting the best employee award in last company. With a strong background and commitment to good and quality results, I am ready to contribute to your company.

### WORKING EXPERIENCE \_

PT. Posco DX Indonesia - Cilegon

Supply Chain Management (Integrated Logistic)

August 2019 - July 2024

Responsibility:

- Provide technical support and guidance to manufacturing personnel and other stakeholders to ensure smooth and efficient SCM operations.
- Manage the transportation system for procurement of goods or carriers and transportation for sending domestic and export products
- Understand document shipping domestic/export according (BL, L/C, Invoice, Packing List, FOB, Payment Term, etc)
- Manage the layout of ready-to-ship products
- Manage transportation for product movement between warehouses
- Manage the bidding system for car, train and ship transportation vendors.
- Analyze and evaluate management system progress to identify opportunities for improvement and increased efficiency.
- Collaborate with IT and other stakeholders to create new business.
- Work with cross-functional teams to ensure that SCM systems are aligned with business needs and objectives.
- Ensure the SCM flow is integrated with other systems and processes, such as SAP, ERP and MES

PT. Sumber Alfaria Trijaya, Tbk - Serang Marketing Design & Warehouse January 2019 - July 2019

Responsibility:

- Manage the receipt of goods from suppliers to the warehouse and arrange delivery transportation from the warehouse to the store
- Create a stock list of goods and inventory in the warehouse
- Create promotional designs and event product layout guides for stores

PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia, Tbk - Serang QA Staff

August 2015 - November 2016

Responsibility:

- Provides frontliner service standard scores (CS, Teller)
- Create a standard service simulation schedule
- Checking the completeness of banking standards
- Ensure everything goes according to SOP
- Provide standard appearance scores for Branch Offices, Units as well as their equipment in accordance with banking standards
- Input assessment results into the internal audit system
- Create QA data reports for internal audit needs

#### SKILL AND LANGUAGE \_

- Banking
- Supply Chani Management
- Data Analyst
- English
- Korean



# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### PERSONAL DATA

Full Name : Ramdhan Akbar Bakhar Place, Date of birth : Bandung, 20 March 1991

Gender : Male
Citizenship : Indonesia
Religion : Islam
Status : Married

Address : Jl. Raya SMAN 1 Kramatwatu No. 3 Rt 07 Rw 14 Subdistric Kramatwatu

Province Banten

Telephone : 0812-8400-0413

Email : akbarbakhar@gmail.com

### FORMAL EDUCATION

1. SD Negeri 2 Serang	: Year 1997	- 2003
2. SMP Negeri 47 Bandung	: Year 2003	- 2006
3. SMA Negeri 4 Kota Serang	: Year 2006	- 2009
4. Universitas Serang Raya (S1- Informatics Engineering)	: Year 2011	- 2015

### **CERTIFICATES AND AWARDS**

1. Computer Courses [MS OFFICE]	: Year 2009
2. Training on Operation and Maintenance Networks for 20 Kv	: Year 2010
3. President Director Award [Best Employee]	: Year 2020

# WORK HISTORY

1. Technician at PT. Mahiza Karya Mandir	: Year 2011	- 2013
2. Staff Adm Technician at PT. Mahiza Karya Mandiri	: Year 2013	- 2014
3. Coordinator Technician at PT. Mahiza Karya Mandiri	: Year 2014	- 2015
4. QA Satff at PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Year 2015	- 2016
5. FS (Funds and Services) at PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Year 2016	- 2017
6. AAO (Asociate Account Officer) di PT. Bank Rakyat Indonesia	: Year 2017	- 2018
7. Marketing Design & Warehouse at PT. Sumber Alfaria Trijaya Tbk	: Year 2019	- 2019
8. Supply Chain Management Analyst System at PT. POSCO DX Indonesia	: Year 2019	- 2024

That's the life story I've made for the truth.

Serang, July 2024

Ramdhan Akbar Bakhar

